They asked for our leader. They got... him.
Elio is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by Madeline Sharafian.
Elio, a space fanatic with an active imagination, finds himself on a cosmic misadventure where he must form new bonds with eccentric
alien lifeforms, navigate a crisis of intergalactic proportions and somehow discover who he is truly meant to be.
Elio / Other Elio (voice), played by Yonas Kibreab.
Glordon (voice), played by Remy Edgerly.
Olga Solís (voice), played by Zoe Saldaña.
Lord Grigon (voice), played by Brad Garrett.
Ambassador Helix (voice), played by Brandon Moon.
Ambassador Questa (voice), played by Jameela Jamil.
Elio is a 2025 American animated science fiction adventure film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Madeline Sharafian, Domee Shi, and Adrian Molina, and written by Julia Cho, Mark Hammer, and Mike Jones, from a story developed by Molina, Sharafian, Shi, and
Cho, the film stars the voices of Yonas Kibreab, Zoe Saldaña, Remy Edgerly, Dylan Gilmer, Matthias Schweighöfer, Brandon Moon, Brad Garrett, and Jameela Jamil.
It follows an eleven-year-old boy named Elio Solís (Kibreab) who is mistaken for the intergalactic ambassador of Earth after being beamed up to the
Communiverse by aliens for making contact, and must navigate a crisis that involves the warlord father of an alien he befriended.
Elio was conceived by Molina as a story about childhood and social isolation and was inspired by growing
up on a military base and his eventual enrollment at the California Institute of the Arts.
The film was officially announced in September
2022, with Molina attached to direct.
Molina later left the project to work on Coco 2 (2029), and in August 2024, it was
announced that Shi and Sharafian would replace him as lead directors.
The production team devised a process, titled the "College Project", to
create the look of the space setting, the Communiverse.
The film was shot with a virtual anamorphic lens and Pixar's new Luna lighting
toolset was used to quickly define lighting and the overall aesthetic.
Its musical score was composed by Rob Simonsen.
Elio premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 10,
2025, and was theatrically released in the United States on June 20.
Although the film received positive reviews from critics, it underperformed at the box office,
grossing $154 million worldwide against an estimated budget of $150–200 million.
The film has been nominated for Best Animated Feature at the Critics' Choice Movie Awards, Golden Globe Awards, and the
Academy Awards, as well as a leading 10 nominations at the 53rd Annie Awards including Best Feature.
The film explores themes of villain, alien, coming of
age, computer animation, eye patch.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.